Guide to the Arthur L. Schawlow Papers SC0554
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Arthur L. Schawlow papers
1949-1997
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Schawlow, Arthur L.
SC0554
98.25 Linear Feet
These papers primarily document Schawlow's career at Stanford and include correspondence, 1951-1995; lecture notes and class files, 1980-1988, containing problem sets and solutions, exams, and other information; grant files; records from participation in professional organizations including American Physical Society, American Institute of Physics, and the Optical Society of America; and reprints of his and his students' articles, 1949-1994. Also included is correspondence, clippings, and brochures pertaining to autism, 1981-1989, including typescript of "Our Autistic Son" by Aurelia T. and Arthur L. Schawlow.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Arthur Schawlow, 1997-1998.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Arthur L. Schawlow, professor of physics at Stanford University from 1961 to 1991, received the Nobel Prize in physics in 1981 for his contributions to the development of laser spectroscopy. He and his brother-in-law, Charles Townes, professor emeritus at the University of California-Berkeley, published their first paper showing how to build a laser in 1958, while Schawlow was a research physicist at Bell Telephone Laboratories. Schawlow earned his B.A., M.A., and Ph.D. at the University of Toronto and was a research associate and associate professor at Columbia University before coming to Stanford. He was chair of the physics department from 1966 to 1970 and retired from active teaching in 1991 with the rank of professor emeritus. He is a fellow of the American Physical Society, the Optical Society of America, the Institute of Electrical Electronics Engineers, the American Association for the Advancement of Science, and the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.
Description of the Collection
These papers primarily document Schawlow's career at Stanford and include correspondence, 1951-1995; lecture notes and class files, 1980-1988, containing problem sets and solutions, exams, and other information; grant files; records from participation in professional organizations including American Physical Society, American Institute of Physics, and the Optical Society of America; and reprints of his and his students' articles, 1949-1994. Also included is correspondence, clippings, and brochures pertaining to autism, 1981-1989, including typescript of "Our Autistic Son" by Aurelia T. and Arthur L. Schawlow.
Microwave spectroscopy.; Lasers.; Autism.; Physics -- Study and teaching.; American Institute of Physics.; Schawlow, Arthur L.; Schawlow, Arthur L.; American Physical Society.; Stanford University. Department of Physics; Optical Society of America.
- Papers, Accession ARCH-1997-091
  - Correspondence Index, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence A, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence B, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence C, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence D, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence E, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence F, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence G, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence H, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence I, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence J, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence K, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence LE, Rong-Rong (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence LARSON, C.E. Videotape Project (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence L, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence M, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence N, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Neil Patterson Scientific American (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Pritchard, David (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence O-P, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Q-R, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence S, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence T, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence U-V, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence W, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence X-Y-Z, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence A, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence B, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence C, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence D, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence T, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence U-V, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence W, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence X-Y-Z, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 2 Calendars, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Chebotayev Visit, 1988 Mar 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence A, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence B, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence C, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence D, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence E, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence F, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence G, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence H, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence I, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence J, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence K, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence L, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence M, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence N, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence O-P, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Q-R, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence S, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence T, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence U-V, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence W, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence X-Y-Z, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence A, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Felix Bloch (efforts), 1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence B, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence C, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence D, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence E, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence F, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence G, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence H, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence I, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence J, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence K, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence L, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence M, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence N, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence O, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence P, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Q, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence R, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence S, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - 2 FER 402 NIST FEE (Professor Chu) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - CMR Grant, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Technical Reports/ Dissertations (Box 6)
  - Technical Reports/ Dissertations (Box 7)
  - Technical Reports/ Dissertations (Box 8)
  - Dictation machine (Box 9)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1998-275
  - Trip Folders/Meetings Attended, 1970s (Box 39087)
  - Trip Folders/Meetings Attended, 1970s and 1980s (Box 7)
  - Trip Folders/Meetings Attended, 1980s (Box 39315)
  - Trip Folders/Meetings Attended, 1980s and 1990s (Box 23)
  - Trip Folders/Meetings Attended, 1970s - 1990s (Box 24)
  - Trip Folders/Meetings Attended, 1960s - 1990s (Box 25)
  - Trip Folders/Meetings Attended, 1990s (Box 26)
  - Trip Folders/Meetings Attended, 1970s and 1990s (Box 27)
  - Trip Folders/Meetings Attended, 1970s - 1990s (Box 28)
  - Trip Folders/Meetings Attended, 1970s and 1990s (Box 29)
  - Trip Folders/Meetings Attended, 1970s (Box 30-31)
  - Trip Folders/Meetings Attended, 1960s - 1970s (Box 32)
  - Trip Folders/Meetings Attended, 1960s (Box 33-35)
  - Trip Folders/Meetings Attended, 1960s - 1970s (Box 36)
  - Trip Folders/Meetings Attended, 1970s (Box 37)
  - Correspondence, 1951 – 1960 (A-C) (Box 37)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (D-F) – 1961 (X-Y-Z) (Box 38)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (A-R) (Box 39)
  - APS Mtg., 1962, Stanford (Box 39)
  - Optical Society (Box 39)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (S) – 1963 (G) (Box 40)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (H) - 1963 (X-Y-Z) (Box 41)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (A-O) (Box 42)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (P) - 1965 (K) (Box 43)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (L) - 1966 (D) (Box 44)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (E-W) (Box 45)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (X-Y-Z) – 1967 (O) (Box 46)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (P) – 1967 (X-Y-Z) (Box 47)
  - Defiance Calendar Refill, 1964-1965 (Box 47)
  - Defiance Calendar Refill, 1966-1967 (Box 47)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (A-L) (Box 48)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (M) - 1969 (B) (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (C) - 1969 (O-P) (Box 50)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Q-R) - 1970 (C) (Box 51)
  - Daily Record of Letters. Received and Sent. Vol. III. May 21, 1968 to Sept. 20, 1971 (Box 51)
  - Office (Box 51)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (D) - 1970 (Q-R) (Box 52)
  - Optics Panel, New York [?], May 22, 1970 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (S) - 1971 (K) (Box 53)
  - S.O.A.P. Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 53)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (L) - 1972 (E) (Box 54)
  - Crane, Langdon (Box 54)
  - Kisliuk, Paul (Box 54)
  - Mandel, Morton (Box 54)
  - Stroke, George (Box 54)
  - Wieder, Irwin (Box 54)
  - Kaminov, I.P. (Box 54)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (F) - 1973 (A) (Box 55)
  - Daily Record of Letters. Received and Sent. Vol. IV. Sept. 20, 1971 to Dec., 1973 (Box 55)
  - Calendar [n.y.] (Box 55)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (B) - 1973 (X-Y-Z) (Box 56)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (A) - 1974 (Q-R) (Box 57)
  - Daily Record of Letters. Received and Sent. Vol. V. January 1974 -. (Box 57)
  - Calendar, 1974 (Box 57)
  - Moravcsik / Moses, 1973-74 (Box 57)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (S) - 1975 (L) (Box 58)
  - Kompanets, O.N. (USSR visitor for several days during Jan/Feb 1975) (Box 58)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (M) - 1976 (F) (Box 59)
  - Calendar, 1976 (Box 59)
  - Agostini, P. (Visiting scholar from Centre d’Etudes Nucleaires de Saclay, Grif-sur-Yvette, France) (Box 59)
  - Chebotarev, Dr. V.P. (USSR / Visitor, Feb. or March 1976. From: Institute of Semiconductors, Academy of Science) (Box 59)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (E) - 1977 (D) (Box 60)
  - Calendar, 1977 (Box 60)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (E) - 1977 (X-Y-Z) (Box 61)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (A) - 1978 (U-V) (Box 62)
  - Calendar and postcards, 1978 (Box 62)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (W) - 1978 (X-Y-Z) (Box 63)
  - Sobchak, Patricia, 1978 (Box 63)
  - Sobchek, P., 1978 (Box 63)
  - A Proposal to the National Science Foundation, 1978 [?] (Box 63)
  - Townes-Feix re Gould, 1978 (Box 63)
  - “Barron’s”, Beb. 27, 1978 (Box 63)
  - Chang, Tong-Han, Professor (Box 63)
  - Calendars, 1979 (Box 63)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (A-S) (Box 64)
  - Retirement, 1979 (Box 64)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (T) - 1980 (K) (Box 65)
  - Dr. T. C. Wang, et. al., visit, Oct. 24-26, 1979 (Box 65)
  - Calendars and correspondence, 1980 (Box 65)
  - Bloch, 75th Birthday (Box 65)
  - J. Merritt Jacobson, Feb. 1980 (Box 65)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (L) – 1980 (X-Y-Z) (Box 66)
  - Marconi (Box 66)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (A-B) (Box 67)
  - Calendars, 1981 (Box 67)
  - Belkin, Bernard, 1980-1982 (Box 67)
  - Burton, Bernard, 1981 (Box 67)
  - Gynecologic Laser Society, 1982 (Box 67)
  - Sidley & Austin, 1981 (Box 67)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (C-M) (Box 68)
  - Djerassi, Carl, 1981 (Box 68)
  - Banquet of the Golden Plate, 1981 (Box 68)
  - Litovchenko, Vladimir (Box 68)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (N) - 1981 (X-Y-Z) (Box 69)
  - Marconi – Int’l Fellowship, Dec. 9[?], 1981 (Alpine, New Jersey) (Box 69)
  - Marconi International Fellowship, 1981 (Box 69)
  - Misc. correspondence, 1981 - 1982 (?) (Box 69)
  - Information Retrieval Comments, 1967-1983 (Box 69)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (A-M) (Box 70)
  - Calendars, 1982 (Box 70)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (N) - 1983 (A) (Box 71)
  - Mishin, V.I., March 15 [n.y.], 1982 (Box 71)
  - [no name], 1982 to 1984 (Box 71)
  - Banquet of the Golden Plate, 1982 (Box 71)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (B-K) (Box 72)
  - Marconi Fellowship, Oct.-Dec.1982 (Box 72)
  - Marconi Int’l Fellowship, 10th Selection Committee, Book 1: 1-8 (Box 72)
  - Marconi Int’l Fellowship, 10th Selection Committee, Book I1: 9-17 (Box 72)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (L-W) (Box 73)
  - Marconi Int’l Fellowship, 10th Selection Committee, Book II1: 18-25 (Box 73)
  - Sontag, H., 1983 (Visiting Scholar: U. Konstanz) (Box 73)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (X-Y-Z) - 1984 (S) (Box 74)
  - Calendars, 1984 (Box 74)
  - EDEE Manuscript (Box 74)
  - Smithsonian Exhibit (Box 74)
  - Harris, Lesley (Box 74)
  - Lindgren, Ingvar, Goteborg, Sweden, Visitor – ALS, Aug. 1-3, 1984 (Box 74)
  - Polish Visitors, request: 12/84 (Box 74)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (T) - 1985 (L) (Box 75)
  - Calendars, 1985 (Box 75)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (M) - 1985 (X-Y-Z) / YUAN, President Yun-Kai, Visit: 11/29 – 12/3/84, East China, Normal U. (Box 76)
  - O’Leary, Sean V., Visiting Scholar (Box 76)
  - Saporoschenko, M. (Box 76)
  - Sabbatical Leave, Spring 1985 (Box 76)
  - Tiffany, Wm. B., 1984 (Box 76)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (A-G) (Box 76)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (H) - 1992 (H) (Box 77)
  - News Articles, 1990 (Box 77)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (J) - 1993 (M) (Box 78)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (N) - 1994 (S) (Box 79)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (T) - 1995 (X-Y-Z) (Box 80)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1975 (A-B) (Box 80)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1975 (C) - 1966-1975 (X-Y-Z) (Box 81)
  - Giraud, Michel (Box 81)
  - Blackwell’s - England (Box 81)
  - Laser Eraser Letters, Jan. 1965 - present (A-N) (Box 81)
  - Laser Eraser Letters, Jan. 1965 - present (O-X/Y/Z) (Box 82)
  - Nota Bene (Box 82)
  - Nota Bene Tutorial (Box 82)
  - Index to Nota Bene Tutorial (Box 82)
  - Photos (Box 82)
  - Model 78-400/1.83 Meter Ebert Vacuum Scanning Spectrometer, Jan. 1962 (Box 82)
  - Lasers for Medicine (Box 82)
  - Sierra Laser Systems, Inc. - A Business Plan for 1985-89, Sept. 1, 1984 (Box 82)
  - Laser Information Letters (Students), 1966 – present (A-X/Y/Z) (Box 83)
  - Laser Reprints Sent (without letters) (Box 83)
  - Laser (Box 83)
  - Miscellaneous Laser - Info (Box 83)
  - “Optical Masers” (Sci. Am. ’61) (Box 83)
  - “Advances Opt. Masers” (Sci. Am. ’63) (Box 83)
  - “Lasers” (Sci. 149, ’65) (Box 83)
  - “Demonstration Laser” (Box 83)
  - Laser – Ref. List (Box 84)
  - Science Year ’65 / “Beam of the Future” (Box 84)
  - A. A. A. S. Fellowship (Box 84)
  - A. A. A. S. Physics Section (Box 84)
  - A. A. A. S. Secretary Section B - Physics (Box 84)
  - A. A. A. S. Annual Mtg. ’80-81 (Box 84)
  - A. A. A. S. Jan.- Oct. 1979 (Box 84)
  - A. A. A. S., Nov. 1979 – Dec. 1980 (Box 85)
  - A. A. A. S. 1979 – Physics – Membership List (Box 85)
  - A. I. P. (American Institute of Physics), March 30, 1979 (Box 85)
  - A. P. S. (The American Physical Society), Vice President Elect, 1979 (Box 85)
  - A. P. S. Fellows (Box 85)
  - A. P. S. Congressional Fellowship (Box 85)
  - A. A. A. S. – Section Chairpersons, 1978 (Box 85)
  - A. P. S., Dec. 1978 (Box 85)
  - A. P. S., Jan. – Sept. 1979 (Box 86)
  - A. P. S. Finance Committee, March 1979 (Box 86)
  - A. P. S., Oct. – Dec. 1979 (Box 87)
  - A. I. P. Governing Board – March 31, 1979 – 3 years (Box 87)
  - A. P. S. Committee on Annual Meeting (Box 87)
  - A. P. S. Finance Committee, 1979 (Box 87)
  - A. P. S. – P.O.P.A. (Box 87)
  - A. P. S. Congressional Fellows (Box 87)
  - A. P. S. Committees, 1979 (Box 87)
  - A. P. S. Nomination (Box 87)
  - A. P. S. Council, Jan. 1980 (Box 87)
  - A. P. S. Meetings – Chicago, Jan. 21-24, 1980 (Box 87)
  - A. P. S., Jan. – May 1980 (Box 88)
  - A. P. S. – P.O.P.A. – New York, Feb. 27, 1980 (Box 88)
  - A. I. P. Governing Board Meeting, March 28-29, 1980, New York, N.Y. (Box 88)
  - A. P. S. Meeting – New York, March 24-28, 1980 (Box 88)
  - A. P. S. Industrial Postdoc. Fellowship (Box 88)
  - A. P. S. Exec. Com. Mtg., March 23, 1980 (New York) (Box 88)
  - Am. Inst. Phys. – New York, March 28-29, 1980 (Box 88)
  - A. P. S., Washington, Apr. 28-30, May 1 (Box 88)
  - A. P. S., June – Nov. 1980 (Box 89)
  - A. P. S. Exec. Com. Mtg., June 1980 (New England) (Box 89)
  - E.R.A. Com., Wash., D.C., Oct. 16, 1980 (Catholic Univ., D.C.) (Box 89)
  - A. I. P. Governing Board – N.J., Oct. 30 – Nov. 1, 1980, cancelled (Box 89)
  - A. P. S. – Exec. Com. / Council Mtg., Nov. 21-22, 1980 (New York) (Box 89)
  - D.E.A.P., Los Angeles, Dec. 1-3, 1980 (Box 89)
  - A. P. S., Dec. 1980 – Feb. 1981 (Box 90)
  - A. P. S. Committees, 1980 (Box 90)
  - P.O.P.A., New York, Jan 23, 1981 (Box 90)
  - A. P. S., New York, Jan. 26-29, 1981 (Box 90)
  - A. P. S. Exec. Comm., March 15, 1981 (Box 90)
  - A. I. P. Assembly of Society Officers, Woodbury, N.Y., March 27, 1981 (Box 90)
  - A. I. P., New York, March 27-28, 1981 (Box 90)
  - A. I. P. Governing Board Meeting, Woodbury, N.Y., March 27-28, 1981 (Box 90)
  - I.U.P.A.P. – U.S.N.C. (Box 91)
  - A. P. S., Baltimore, April 20-23, 1981 (Box 91)
  - P.O.P.A., Baltimore, April 21, 1981, Baltimore Hilton, 9 am (Box 91)
  - A. P. S., March – May 1981 (Box 91)
  - A. P. S., June - July 1981 (Box 92)
  - A. P. S. Exec. Committee, June 21-24, 1981 (Highlands Inn, Carmel) (Box 92)
  - President’s Report (Box 92)
  - A. P. S. – Study on Research Planning for Goal Utilization and Synthetic Fuel Production, Final Report, June 1981 (Box 92)
  - The A. I. P. Journal System: Relationships of Price, Page Charges, Demand, Cost and Income, June 1981 (Box 92)
  - A. P. S. - Correspondence (Box 92)
  - Institute for Defense, Analyses (Box 92)
  - A. P. S., August – Dec. 1981 (Box 93)
  - Misc. A. P. S. Communications (Box 93)
  - A. P. S. – Committees, 1981 (Box 93)
  - L. Cranberg (Box 93)
  - A. P. S. – Study on Research Planning for Goal Utilization and Synthetic Fuel Production, Draft Report, April 1981 (Box 94)
  - A. P. S. Meeting – San Francisco, Jan. 25-28, 1982 (Box 94)
  - A. P. S., Jan. – May 1982 (Box 94)
  - A. P. S. Contest, Jan. 26, 1982 (Box 94)
  - A. P. S. Meeting – Washington, D.C., April 26-29, 1982 (Box 94)
  - A. P. S., June 1982 – Jan. 1983 (Box 95)
  - A. P. S. Executive Committee, June 21-23, 1982 (Long Island, New York) (Box 95)
  - A. P. S. - Correspondence (Box 95)
  - A. P. S., Feb. – Dec. 1983 (Box 96)
  - A. P. S., San Francisco (Nov. 21-23, 1983) (Box 96)
  - Freshman Orientation, Sept. 29, 1978 (Box 96)
  - OHIO State University, Columbus, Oct. 3, 1978 (Box 96)
  - M.I.T. Physics Colloquium, Oct. 5, 1978 (Box 96)
  - Colloquium – U.C.L.A., Oct. 12, 1978 (Box 96)
  - Lasag, Thun, Oct. 31 – Nov. 1, 1978 (Box 96)
  - Conference on Innovation, U.C. Santa Cruz, Nov. 9-16, 1978 (Box 96)
  - Univ. of Illinois, Nov. 16, 1978 (Box 96)
  - Adolph Lomb, Com. 1966-67 (Box 96)
  - Adolph Lomb – Medal (Box 96)
  - I.V.E.S. Medals (Box 97)
  - Davisson-Germer Prize, 1965-66, 1970 (Box 97)
  - I.E.E.E. Field Award Subcommittee – 1971, Morris N. Liebmann Memorial Prize Award (Box 97)
  - Optical Society of America (O.S.A.) (Box 97)
  - O.S.A. Committees, 1974-75 (Box 98)
  - O.S.A., August – Sept. 1975 (Box 98)
  - O.S.A. – S.O.A.P. Committee, Feb. 26-27, 1976 (Box 99)
  - O.S.A., Spring Mtg., March 17-21, 1975 (Anaheim) (Box 99)
  - O.S.A., Oct. 1975 – Feb. 1976 (Box 99)
  - O.S.A. – Boston, Oct. 20-24, 1975 (Box 99)
  - A. I. P. – Society Relations (Box 99)
  - O.S.A. Finance (Box 99)
  - S.O.A.P. Committee (Box 99)
  - I.C.O. (Box 99)
  - O.S.A. Appointments (Box 99)
  - O.S.A. – Committee of Scientific Society Presidents (Box 99)
  - O.S.A. Committees, 1974 - 1976 (Box 99)
  - O.S.A., March – Dec. 1976 (Box 100)
  - Directors Meeting, June 1976 (Box 100)
  - O.S.A. Congressional Fellows (Box 100)
  - Turvy Topsy Contest (Box 100)
  - S.O.A.P. Committee (Box 100)
  - O.S.A. – Tucson, Arizona, Oct. 18-23, 1976 (Box 100)
  - Jazz – S.C.I.R.E. (Stud. Center for Innovation in Research and Education) (Box 100)
  - S.C.I.R.E., 1972-1973 (Box 101)
  - Misc. papers (Box 101)
  - Prism productions (Box 101)
  - Laser – Printing Plates (the folder is empty) (Box 101)
  - Laser – Graphic Systems (the folder is empty) (Box 101)
  - A.L.T. & L.P.C. (Ron Barker) – August 1970 - present (Box 101)
  - I.L.C., Inc. (Nov. 1971 – present) (Box 101)
  - Opteach / Optics Technology (Box 102)
  - N.S.F. Teaching Prog. (Box 102)
  - Text Interference – N.S.F. Project (Box 102)
  - Optics Technology (Box 102)
  - Isoray (Box 102)
  - Clippings, 1970-1979; 1981; 1983 (Box 103)
  - Reprints by others, Allen, P.W. – Dexter, D.L. (Box 104)
  - Reprints by others, Dieke, G.H. – Hänsch, T. (Box 105)
  - Reprints by others, Harris, S.E. – Imbusch, G.F. (Box 106)
  - Holograms (Box 106)
  - Jakobs Thesis (Box 106)
  - Reprints by others, Kasevich, Mark – Moerner, W.E. (Box 107)
  - Maser Photos (Box 107)
  - Reprints by others, Mollenauer, L.F. – Schiff, Leonard I. (Box 108)
  - Schawlow, A.L. (Box 108)
  - Reprints by others, Schulz, H.W. – Varsanyi, F. (Box 109)
  - Reprints by others, Vogel, Sy – Zweng, H. Christian (Box 110)
  - Misc. reprints (Box 110)
  - Schawlow reprints, 1949-51 (Box 110)
  - Schawlow reprints, 1952-1961 (Box 111)
  - Schawlow reprints, 1961 (cont’d) - 1963 (Box 112)
  - Schawlow reprints, 1963 (cont’d) - 1965 (Box 113)
  - Schawlow reprints, 1965 (cont’d) - 1967 (Box 114)
  - Schawlow reprints, 1967 (cont’d) - 1968 (Box 115)
  - Schawlow reprints, 1969-1971; 1975; n.d. (Box 116)
  - Schawlow reprints, 1971 (cont’d) – 1972 (Box 117)
  - Image amplifier - Glossys (Box 117)
  - GRM Books - 1971 (Box 117)
  - Schawlow reprints, 1972 (cont’d) - 1975 (Box 118)
  - Schawlow reprints & journals, 1975 (cont’d) - 1977 (Box 119)
  - Schawlow reprints & journals, 1977 (cont’d) – 1978; n.d. (Box 120)
  - Pre/reprints filled, S/144 – S/145 (Box 120)
  - Schawlow reprints & journals, 1979-1980 (Box 121)
  - Misc. reprints (Box 121)
  - Schawlow reprints & journals, 1980 (cont’d) - 1981 (Box 122)
  - Schawlow reprints & journals, 1982 (Box 123)
  - [No name], May 1970 (Box 123)
  - Galley proofs, 1982 (Box 123)
  - Reprints filled, S/168 (Box 123)
  - Misc. reprints (Box 123)
  - No pre/reprint available (Box 123)
  - “Do not take from this folder” (Box 123)
  - Talks – NOT available (Box 123)
  - Schawlow reprints & journals, 1982 (cont’d) (Box 124)
  - Photos (Box 124)
  - Schawlow reprints & journals, 1983-1984 (Box 125)
  - Schawlow reprints & journals, 1984 (cont’d) - 1985 (Box 126)
  - Schawlow reprints & journals, 1985 (cont’d) - 1986 (Box 127)
  - Misc., 1982-1986 (Box 127)
  - Schawlow reprints & journals, 1987-1988 (Box 128)
  - S/194 – Michelson – Morley Centennial Conference Proceedings (Box 128)
  - Copyright forms (Box 128)
  - Classification - PACS (Box 128)
  - Misc., 1984-85 (Box 128)
  - Yen, W.M. (Box 128)
  - Schawlow reprints & journals, 1989-1994; n.d. (Box 129)
  - M. Mayfeh, Saturation Spectrometer (Box 129)
  - Schawlow reprints & journals, 1958; 1989; 1994-1997 (Box 130)
  - Student reprints (Sg 615-624), 1983-1985 (Box 130)
  - Student reprints (Sg 625-640), 1985-87 (Box 131)
  - Student reprints (Sg 641-644), 1987 (cont’d) – 1989; (Sg 589-596), 1980 (Box 132)
  - Student reprints (Sg 597-607), 1981-82 (Box 133)
  - Student reprints (Sg 608-614), 1981-82; (Sg 557-559), 1974-1975 (Box 134)
  - Student reprints (Sg 560-568), 1975 (cont’d) - 1976 (Box 135)
  - Student reprints (Sg 569-578), 1977-78 (Box 136)
  - Student reprints (Sg 579-588), 1978 (cont’d) – 1979; (Sg 526-529), 1968-1969 (Box 137)
  - Student reprints (Sg 530-539), 1970-1971 (Box 138)
  - Student reprints (Sg 539A-548), 1971 (cont’d) - 1973 (Box 139)
  - Student reprints (Sg 549-556), 1973 (cont’d) – 1974; (Sg 501-508), 1964-1966; unpublished (Box 140)
  - Student reprints (Sg 509-519), 1966 (cont’d) - 1968 (Box 141)
  - Student reprints (Sg 520-525), 1968 (cont’d) - 1969 (Box 142)
  - A. P. S. – Expense Forms (Box 142)
  - American Express Travel Card Information, 1984 (Box 142)
  - American Philosophical Society (Box 142)
  - Consultec (Box 142)
  - Excel Precision Corp. (Box 142)
  - John Tsai – Regarding Excel Technology (Box 142)